<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>machine learning on Mohamed Kouhou&#39;s personal website</title>
    <link>https://kouhoumed.site/tags/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in machine learning on Mohamed Kouhou&#39;s personal website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kouhoumed.site/tags/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Supervised Learning algorithms with R (part 2)</title>
      <link>https://kouhoumed.site/blog/supervised-algorithms-with-r-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kouhoumed.site/blog/supervised-algorithms-with-r-2/</guid>
      <description>In a previous article, we have explained the principles of K-Nearest Neighbours and Decision Trees and seen hands-on examples of how these models can be created using R programming language. In this article, we will continue on the same track and see other supervised learning algorithms, namely Linear Regression and Logistic Regression.
Linear Regression  Linear Regression is a predictive model used to predict the outcome value of an outcome variable Y based on one or more input predictor variables X.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supervised Learning algorithms with R (part 1)</title>
      <link>https://kouhoumed.site/blog/supervised-learning-algorithms-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kouhoumed.site/blog/supervised-learning-algorithms-r/</guid>
      <description>As I mentioned in an earlier post, machine learning algorithms are categorized into three main types :
 Supervised learning algorithms Unsupervised learning algorithms Reinfocement learning algorithms  In this article, we will only talk about some of machine learning supervised algorithms. We&amp;rsquo;ll also see examples using R programming language.
First of all, I would like to remind you that supervised learning is a machine learning algorithm that tries to find a function mapping an input to a given output based on a set of examples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is machine learning ?</title>
      <link>https://kouhoumed.site/blog/ml/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kouhoumed.site/blog/ml/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;What we want is a machine that can learn from experience&amp;rdquo;
Alan Turing, 1947
 What is machine learning ? Machine learning is a form of artificial intelligence (AI) that allows a system to learn from data without explicitly programming the instructions to be executed. However, machine learning is not a simple process. As the algorithms ingest the training data, it becomes possible to create more accurate models based on that data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Blockchain Technology?</title>
      <link>https://kouhoumed.site/blog/blockchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kouhoumed.site/blog/blockchain/</guid>
      <description>MathJax Test $$\int x^3 dx$$
Code highlighting Test if(FALSE) { &amp;#34;This is a demo for multi-line comments and it should be put inside either a single OR double quote&amp;#34; } myString &amp;lt;- &amp;#34;Hello, World!&amp;#34; print ( myString) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Language Processing (NLP)</title>
      <link>https://kouhoumed.site/blog/nlp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kouhoumed.site/blog/nlp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lorem est tota propiore conpellat pectoribus de
pectora summo.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Data Science ?</title>
      <link>https://kouhoumed.site/blog/ds/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kouhoumed.site/blog/ds/</guid>
      <description>“You can have data without information, but you cannot have information without data.” – Daniel Keys Moran
 Data science is one of the most debated topics in the industries these days. Its popularity has grown over the years, and companies have started implementing data science techniques to grow their business and increase customer satisfaction. According to a study conducted in 2013, 90% of the world&amp;rsquo;s data has been produced within the previous two years.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
